'You Can't Hold your Breath & Scream at the Same Time'
The Rift is a action, horror, mystery film directed by Juan Piquer Simón.
An experimental submarine with a very experienced crew, the "Siren II" is sent to find out what
happened to the "Siren I" after it mysteriously disappeared in a submarine rift.
Things go awry when they begin to find things that shouldn't be there...
Wick Hayes, played by Jack Scalia.
Captain Phillips, played by R. Lee Ermey.
Robbins, played by Ray Wise.
Lt. Nina Crowley, played by Deborah Adair.
Joe Kane, played by John Toles-Bey.
Ana Rivera, played by Ely Pouget.
The Rift (Spanish: La grieta) is a 1990 Spanish science-fiction horror film
directed by Juan Piquer Simón and starring Jack Scalia, R.
Lee Ermey and Ray Wise.
The story concerns Wick Hayes (Scalia), an engineer who is blamed for the disappearance of the submarine he designed, and
leads an investigation team to the depths of the ocean, where he encounters an array of abnormal creatures.
Part of a wave of underwater fantasy films released around
1989, it was retitled Endless Descent for the U.S.
The film explores themes of monster, submarine,
giant monster, underwater, giant fish.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.